Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we're talking about a very, well, it's a pretty important part of your child's education.
我是Catherine，今天我们讨论一个非常……嗯，可以说是孩子教育中相当重要的一部分。
That's right. Something that many schools do is they have a conference between the teacher and the parent.
没错。很多学校都会做的一件事，就是老师和家长之间开个会。
So, you know, they can talk about how the child is doing.
所以，你知道，他们可以聊聊孩子表现如何。
That's right. So this is something very common in American schools and it's important to learn some of the words that you will hear.
没错。这在美国学校很常见，学习一些你会听到的词汇很重要。
So let's take a listen to our dialogue and when we come back we'll be talking about what some of these words and phrases mean.
那么，我们先来听一下对话，回来后再聊聊这些单词和短语的意思。
Thank you for coming tonight, Mr. Weber.
谢谢您今晚能来，Weber先生。
As a teacher, it's great seeing the kids' parents assist our parent-teacher conference tonight.
作为老师，看到孩子们的家长来参加今晚的家长会，真是太好了。
Of course. I'm very interested to know how my child is doing and also get some insight from you as to how he can improve.
当然。我很想知道孩子表现如何，也想从您这里得到一些关于他如何提高的见解。
Well, Alan is a great student. He's a hard worker and very well behaved.
嗯，Alan是个好学生。他很用功，表现也很好。
However, he does struggle a bit with math.
不过，他在数学上确实有点吃力。
I guess he gets that from me. I never did well in math when I was a kid.
我想这点是遗传了我。我小时候数学从来就不好。
What can I do at home to complement what he is learning in the classroom?
我在家能做些什么来配合他在课堂上学的东西呢？
Well, it's important that you sit with him and review his homework assignments and help him with math.
嗯，重要的是你要陪他一起复习家庭作业，并帮他学数学。
I would also recommend he stay after school twice a week for tutoring sessions. It will really help a lot.
我还建议他每周放学后参加两次辅导课。这会很有帮助。
Thanks a lot. I will definitely do that. Is there anything else?
非常感谢。我一定会照做的。还有其他事吗？
Um, yes. Here's a notice from our financial department. Seems your child's tuition is overdue.
嗯，有的。这是财务部门的一份通知。看来您孩子的学费逾期了。
Oh, yes. I...
哦，是的。我……
All right, we're back. So now let's take a look at some language takeaway.
好了，我们回来了。现在来看看一些语言要点。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
First up in language takeaway, we have the key phrase here, which is parent-teacher conference.
首先在语言要点部分，我们有一个关键短语，就是“家长会”。
That's right. So it's a parent-teacher conference, a parent-teacher conference.
没错。所以是家长会，家长会。
And it's basically a meeting between the parent of the child and the teacher of the child.
它基本上就是孩子家长和老师之间的会议。
And they talk about how well he is doing or she is doing or what she needs or he needs to improve.
他们会讨论孩子表现如何，或者需要改进什么。
That's right. So this is something that can happen maybe twice a year, maybe four times a year.
对。所以这通常一年发生两次，或者四次。
It depends on the school, but it's just a meeting between the parents or parent of the child and his or her teacher.
取决于学校，但就是孩子家长和老师之间的会议。
That's right. So it's very common with schools in order to make sure that the parent knows how the child is doing in school and can improve maybe.
没错。这在学校很常见，目的是让家长了解孩子在学校的表现，并可能帮助改进。
And one of the goals is to provide the parent with insight into how to help the child learn more.
其中一个目标是让家长深入了解如何帮助孩子学得更多。
OK. So insight is kind of like a better understanding of things.
好的。所以“insight”有点像对事情更深入的理解。
More clear picture. Yeah. So I could say, you know what, Marco, I just don't get that woman, Cindy.
更清晰的画面。是的。所以我可以这么说，Marco，我就是搞不懂那个女人Cindy。
Can you provide some insight into why she made that decision?
你能给我一些见解，解释她为什么做那个决定吗？
That's right. So you want some more information or some type of explanation as to why she made that decision.
没错。所以你希望得到更多信息或某种解释，说明她为什么做那个决定。
Exactly. And so the teacher will then provide this insight by describing what he or she thinks about the student.
正是。所以老师会通过描述他对学生的看法来提供这种见解。
That's right. And while the teacher went on to say that Alan is a great student, hard worker, very well behaved.
没错。老师接着说Alan是个好学生，很努力，表现很好。
So he is a hard worker. That means he is this is not an address.
所以他是个努力的人。这不是一个地址。
This is now he is a hard worker. She is a hard worker. He is very well behaved.
这是说他是个努力的人。她是个努力的人。他表现很好。
Now, this is a way to describe him. He is not naughty. He is well behaved.
这是一种描述他的方式。他不调皮，他表现很好。
That means he doesn't start fights. He doesn't talk in class. He doesn't cheat.
这意味着他不打架，不在课堂上讲话，不作弊。
OK, so what would be the opposite? You say a child or a person is well behaved. What would be the opposite?
好的，那反义词是什么？你说一个孩子或一个人表现好。反义词是什么？
I would say the the child who is not well behaved is naughty.
我会说表现不好的孩子是调皮的。
OK, so you say he is not well behaved or just he is naughty.
好，所以你是说他表现不好，或者只是说他很调皮？
He's very naughty. He always starts fights in class.
他非常调皮。他总是在课堂上挑起争斗。
OK, now the student is having a little bit of problems with math.
好，现在这个学生在数学上遇到了一些问题。
And so the parent asks what he can do to complement what he is learning in the classroom.
于是家长问，他能做些什么来补充孩子在课堂上学到的东西。
OK, so to complement, you might have heard this verb before, but here it means something special.
好，所以“补充”这个词，你可能以前听过这个动词，但在这里它有特殊含义。
It means to add to. All right. So, OK, the boy, Alan, he's learning a lot in school,
它的意思是“增加”。好吧。所以，这个男孩艾伦在学校学了很多东西，
but maybe he's not learning enough because his math scores just aren't good enough.
但也许他学得不够，因为他的数学成绩就是不够好。
So the father wants to know what can he do in addition to school.
所以父亲想知道，除了学校之外，他还能做些什么。
Right. You know, what can he do extra to help his boy so that will it will complement his studies.
对。你知道，他能额外做些什么来帮助他的儿子，从而补充他的学习。
That's right. So we have to complement someone as to say, oh, you look nice today
没错。所以我们说“赞美”某人，比如“哦，你今天看起来不错”，
or this in this situation, this verb we are saying to provide more support or extra help to something.
或者在这个情况下，这个动词我们说的是提供更多支持或额外帮助。
That's right. So I feel really good about accounting, but I want to take an extra math class
对。所以我对会计感觉很好，但我想多上一门数学课，
to complement my accounting studies because I'm just not very confident in my math.
来补充我的会计学习，因为我对自己的数学不太自信。
Very good. Exactly. All right. So and towards the end, well, we're talking about how the child's tuition is overdue.
很好。没错。好吧。所以到最后，我们谈到孩子的学费逾期了。
The teacher says the child's tuition is overdue. What is tuition, Marco?
老师说孩子的学费逾期了。什么是学费，马可？
Well, the tuition is the fees that you have to pay for school.
嗯，学费是你必须为学校支付的费用。
OK, so maybe a private school will have a tuition. So a high school or an elementary school.
好，所以可能私立学校会有学费。比如高中或小学。
But you often hear this in regards to college or university. So college tuitions in America are very expensive.
但你经常听到这个词与大学或学院相关。所以美国的大学学费非常贵。
That's right. And when a tuition is overdue, it means that it hasn't been paid yet.
没错。当学费逾期时，意味着它还没有支付。
And so the payment is late. The payment is late. Now, a lot of things can be overdue.
所以付款晚了。付款晚了。现在，很多东西都可能逾期。
That means they've passed their due date. A bill can be overdue.
那意味着它们已经过了到期日。账单可能会逾期。
That's right. So you should have paid your bill already, but you haven't. So it's overdue.
没错。所以你应该已经付了账单，但你没有，所以它逾期了。
OK, so a lot of vocab there. Why don't we listen to our dialogue again?
好的，这里有很多词汇。我们不如再听一遍对话？
Thank you for coming tonight, Mr. Weber. As a teacher, it's great seeing the kids' parents
感谢您今晚能来，韦伯先生。作为一名老师，看到孩子们的家长来参加我们的家长会，真是太好了。
assist our parent-teacher conference night.
协助我们的家长会之夜。
Of course. I am very interested to know how my child is doing and also get some insight from you as to how he can improve.
当然。我非常想知道我的孩子表现如何，也想从您这里得到一些关于他如何改进的见解。
Well, Alan is a great student. He's a hard worker and very well behaved. However, he does struggle a bit with math.
嗯，艾伦是个好学生。他很努力，表现也很好。不过，他在数学上确实有点吃力。
I guess he gets that from me. I never did well in math when I was a kid.
我想他是遗传了我。我小时候数学从来就不好。
What can I do at home to complement what he is learning in the classroom?
我在家能做些什么来补充他在课堂上学到的东西呢？
Well, it's important that you sit with him and review his homework assignments and help him with math.
嗯，重要的是你要和他一起复习他的家庭作业，并帮助他学数学。
I would also recommend he stay after school twice a week for tutoring sessions. It will really help a lot.
我还建议他每周两次放学后留下来参加辅导课。这真的会很有帮助。
Thanks a lot. I will definitely do that. Is there anything else?
非常感谢。我一定会这么做的。还有其他事吗？
Um, yes. Here's a notice from our financial department. Seems your child's tuition is overdue.
嗯，是的。这是我们财务部门的一份通知。看来您孩子的学费逾期了。
Oh, yes.
哦，是的。
I...
我……
Alright, we're back. So now we've prepared three key phrases for you on Fluency Builder.
好了，我们回来了。现在我们在流利度构建器中为您准备了三个关键短语。
Fluency Builder
流利度构建器
Alright, the first phrase here on Fluency Builder is to struggle with. So, Alan is a great student, but he does struggle with math.
好的，流利度构建器中的第一个短语是“struggle with”。所以，艾伦是个好学生，但他确实在数学上很吃力。
That's right. So, to struggle with something means that you are having a hard time. It's difficult for you.
没错。所以，“struggle with something”意味着你遇到了困难。这对你来说很难。
It is difficult. So, when I was a student in elementary school, I struggled with science. Is there anything you struggled with, Marco?
这确实很难。所以，当我在小学时，我在科学上很吃力。马可，你有什么吃力的事情吗？
I struggled with... I struggled a little bit with history.
我在……我在历史方面有点吃力。
Interesting. So, for Marco, history was hard. For me, science was hard.
有意思。所以，对 Marco 来说，历史很难。对我来说，科学很难。
But you can also use it for your work, right? You can say, I'm struggling a little bit at work.
但你也可以用它来形容工作，对吧？你可以说，我在工作上有点吃力。
I'm struggling with my new schedule. I have too much to do.
我在适应新日程上有点吃力。我要做的事情太多了。
Okay. So, after the teacher said that Alan is struggling with math, the parent actually said, I guess he gets that from me.
好的。所以，在老师说 Alan 在数学上吃力之后，家长实际上说，我猜他是遗传我的。
I never did well in math when I was a kid. So, what is the parent saying?
我小时候数学从来都不好。那么，家长在说什么呢？
He gets that from me or she gets that from me. This means that the child has the same problems the parent has.
他遗传我的，或者她遗传我的。这意味着孩子有和家长一样的问题。
So, when the parent was little, he had a hard time with math. He struggled with math.
所以，当家长小时候，他在数学上很吃力。他在数学上挣扎过。
And now his child struggles with math. So, it's something that maybe he inherited or he got from his father.
现在他的孩子在数学上挣扎。所以，这可能是他遗传或从他父亲那里得来的东西。
Right.
对。
He gets that from me.
他遗传我的。
Right. So, sometimes you will hear that maybe somebody is stubborn and you say, well, you know, I get that from my dad.
对。所以，有时候你会听到，也许某人很固执，然后你说，嗯，你知道，我遗传我爸爸的。
Yes. I'm very talkative. I get that from my mother. That means my mother is talkative and I have the same characteristic.
是的。我很健谈。我遗传我妈妈的。这意味着我妈妈很健谈，我有同样的特点。
So, we're basically saying that you kind of genetically inherit the same characteristics.
所以，我们基本上是在说，你有点遗传了同样的特征。
Exactly.
没错。
All right. And the teacher said that, well, in order to improve, Alan should attend tutoring sessions.
好的。老师说，为了进步，Alan 应该参加辅导课。
Tutoring sessions. Now, this is important. You might have heard the word tutor before.
辅导课。现在，这很重要。你可能以前听过“tutor”这个词。
I have a math tutor. But a tutoring session is actually the time you spend together with your tutor practicing something or studying something.
我有一个数学家教。但辅导课实际上是你和家教一起练习或学习某样东西的时间。
Right. So, you don't have a class with your tutor. You have a tutoring session.
对。所以，你和家教不是上课。你是有辅导课。
That's right. Class is for a teacher and many students. But a tutoring session is one-on-one.
没错。课是针对老师和很多学生的。但辅导课是一对一的。
It's two people together, a tutor and a student, a learner.
是两个人在一起，一个家教和一个学生，一个学习者。
So, the word tutor can be a noun. You have a tutor, which is a person that helps you or you can tutor someone.
所以，“tutor”这个词可以是名词。你有一个家教，也就是帮助你的人，或者你可以辅导别人。
To tutor, which means to teach or to help.
辅导，意思是教或帮助。
That's right. So, in college, I had a tutoring session with a math tutor two times a week.
对。所以，在大学里，我每周有两次和数学家教的辅导课。
That means my math tutor helped me learn math outside of school, after school.
这意味着我的数学家教在校外、放学后帮我学数学。
Very good. Alright. So, a lot of great stuff there. Let's listen to the dialogue one last time.
非常好。好的。所以，有很多好东西。让我们最后听一遍对话。
Thank you for coming tonight, Mr. Weber. As a teacher, it's great seeing the kids' parents assist our parent-teacher conference tonight.
感谢您今晚来，Weber 先生。作为老师，看到孩子们的家长参加今晚的家长会，真是太好了。
Of course. I'm very interested to know how my child is doing and also get some insight from you as to how he can improve.
当然。我很想知道我的孩子表现如何，也想从您这里得到一些关于他如何进步的见解。
Well, Alan is a great student. He's a hard worker and very well behaved. However, he does struggle a bit with math.
嗯，Alan 是个好学生。他很努力，表现也很好。不过，他在数学上确实有点吃力。
I guess he gets that from me. I never did well in math when I was a kid.
我猜他是遗传我的。我小时候数学从来都不好。
What can I do at home to complement what he is learning in the classroom?
我在家能做些什么来补充他在课堂上学到的东西？
Well, it's important that you sit with him and review his homework assignments and help him with math.
嗯，重要的是你要和他一起坐，复习他的家庭作业，并帮助他学数学。
I would also recommend he stay after school twice a week for tutoring sessions. It will really help a lot.
我还建议他每周放学后留校两次参加辅导课。这会很有帮助。
Thanks a lot. I will definitely do that. Is there anything else?
非常感谢。我一定会照做。还有其他事吗？
Um, yes. Here's a notice from our financial department. Seems your child's tuition is overdue.
嗯，是的。这是财务部门的一份通知。看来您孩子的学费逾期了。
Oh, yes. I...
哦，是的。我……
Alright. So, parent-teacher conferences, a very common thing. A very common thing.
好的。所以，家长会，一件非常常见的事。一件非常常见的事。
And I think sometimes even a little bit scary for the kid because, you know, your parent is going to go talk to your teacher
而且我觉得有时候对孩子来说甚至有点吓人，因为，你知道，你的家长要去和你的老师谈话，
and maybe your teacher is not going to say great things about you.
也许你的老师不会说你的好话。
Yeah, this is always very nerve-wracking for children because maybe you didn't tell your mom and dad
是的，这对孩子来说总是很紧张，因为也许你没有告诉爸爸妈妈你上周科学考试得了多少分，
what you got on your test in science last week and then your teacher will tell your parents and your parents will be angry.
然后你的老师会告诉你的父母，你的父母会生气。
Right.
对。
So, this is the time when the parents can be honest with the teacher and the teacher can be honest with the parents.
所以，这是家长可以对老师坦诚、老师也可以对家长坦诚的时候。
That's right because sometimes teachers will have a file with maybe your test scores and they will show them to your parents.
没错，因为有时候老师会有一个文件夹，里面可能有你的考试成绩，他们会拿给你父母看。
So, not only what you get on your report card but then you actually see the tests and it could be like you say a little nerve-wracking.
所以，不仅是你成绩单上的分数，而且你还会看到实际的试卷，这可能就像你说的那样有点紧张。
I've also heard though it can be nerve-wracking for the teacher because sometimes teachers have to tell parents things
不过我也听说过，这对老师来说也可能很紧张，因为有时候老师必须告诉家长一些他们不想知道的孩子的事情。
that they don't really want to know about their kids.
对。
Right.
If the teacher says, hey, your boy Alan, he's not very good at math, maybe Alan's dad gets angry.
如果老师说，嘿，你的儿子 Alan，他数学不太好，也许 Alan 的爸爸会生气。
Right.
对。
And says, yo, no, that's not true. He's very good at math.
然后说，哟，不，那不是真的。他数学很好。
Right, right.
对，对。
So, it can be hard for everyone but I think generally they're very positive. They really help the students.
所以，对每个人来说可能都很难，但我觉得通常它们都很积极。它们真的能帮助学生。
Right.
对。
Well, it's interesting and actually I haven't really seen parent-teacher conferences to be that common outside of the United States.
嗯，这很有趣，实际上我还没见过家长会在美国以外那么普遍。
So, maybe if you're a parent, you have attended a parent-teacher conference or maybe when you were a kid, your parents went to your parent-teacher conference.
所以，也许如果你是个家长，你参加过家长会，或者当你还是个孩子时，你的父母去过你的家长会。
And if you don't have teacher conference, parent-teacher conferences in your country, what do you have?
如果你们国家没有家长会，那你们有什么？
How do parents and teachers talk?
家长和老师怎么交流？
Let us know. Our website is EnglishPod.com.
告诉我们。我们的网站是 EnglishPod.com。
All right. We'll see you guys there.
好的。我们到时候见。
Bye.
再见。
Music
音乐